export const chapter = "Chapter - 6: Respiration in Organisms ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "What is respiration in living organisms primarily responsible for?",
          optionA: "Reproduction",
          optionB: "Release of energy from food",
          optionC: "Transportation of nutrients",
          correctAnswer: "b) Release of energy from food",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which type of respiration occurs in the absence of oxygen and may produce alcohol or lactic acid?",
          optionA: "Aerobic respiration",
          optionB: "Anaerobic respiration",
          optionC: "Cellular respiration",
          correctAnswer: "b) Anaerobic respiration",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the chemical representation of anaerobic respiration?",
          optionA: "Glucose + Oxygen → Carbon Dioxide + Water",
          optionB: "Glucose → Alcohol or Lactic Acid + Carbon Dioxide + Energy",
          optionC: "Glucose + Oxygen → Energy + Water",
          correctAnswer:
            "b) Glucose → Alcohol or Lactic Acid + Carbon Dioxide + Energy",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What part of the respiratory system is responsible for moistening the air and trapping germs?",
          optionA: "Trachea",
          optionB: "Nostrils",
          optionC: "Bronchioles",
          correctAnswer: "b) Nostrils",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How is oxygen transported from the lungs to the blood in the respiratory system?",
          optionA: "Through bronchi",
          optionB: "Through alveoli",
          optionC: "Through trachea",
          correctAnswer: "b) Through alveoli",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which organ protects the lungs and lies in the chest cavity on either side of the heart?",
          optionA: "Diaphragm",
          optionB: "Liver",
          optionC: "Rib cage",
          correctAnswer: "c) Rib cage",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the process of taking in air called?",
          optionA: "Inhalation",
          optionB: "Exhalation",
          optionC: "Respiration",
          correctAnswer: "a) Inhalation",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which respiratory disease is caused by an infectious viral agent and includes symptoms like sneezing and fever?",
          optionA: "Asthma",
          optionB: "Yawning",
          optionC: "Flu",
          correctAnswer: "c) Flu",
        },
        {
          question: "How do insects like cockroaches and grasshoppers breathe?",
          optionA: "Through lungs",
          optionB: "Through gills",
          optionC: "Through spiracles and trachea",
          correctAnswer: "c) Through spiracles and trachea",
        },
        {
          question: "How do plants exchange gases during respiration?",
          optionA: "Through specialized respiratory organs",
          optionB: "Through stomata on leaves",
          optionC: "Through gills in the roots",
          correctAnswer: "b) Through stomata on leaves",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Respiration is the process of breaking down of ____ to release energy.",
          optionA: "Water",
          optionB: "Air",
          optionC: "Food",
          correctAnswer: "c) Food",
        },
        {
          question:
            "During cellular respiration, glucose is oxidized in the presence of ____ to release energy, water, and carbon dioxide.",
          optionA: "Nitrogen",
          optionB: "Oxygen",
          optionC: "Hydrogen",
          correctAnswer: "b) Oxygen",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Anaerobic respiration may produce alcohol or lactic acid in the absence of ____. ",
          optionA: "Carbon dioxide",
          optionB: "Water",
          optionC: "Oxygen",
          correctAnswer: "c) Oxygen",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The warm blood flowing through the blood vessels in the nostrils warms the inhaled ____. ",
          optionA: "Nitrogen",
          optionB: "Oxygen",
          optionC: "Carbon dioxide",
          correctAnswer: "b) Oxygen",
        },
        {
          question: "The common passage for air and food is the ____. ",
          optionA: "Trachea",
          optionB: "Pharynx",
          optionC: "Bronchi",
          correctAnswer: "b) Pharynx",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Exchange of oxygen and carbon dioxide takes place in tiny air sacs called ____. ",
          optionA: "Nostrils",
          optionB: "Bronchioles",
          optionC: "Alveoli",
          correctAnswer: "c) Alveoli",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The number of times a person inhales or exhales in a minute is called the ____ rate. ",
          optionA: "Heart",
          optionB: "Breathing",
          optionC: "Pulse",
          correctAnswer: "b) Breathing",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Insects like cockroaches have special air holes on their body surface called ____. ",
          optionA: "Alveoli",
          optionB: "Spiracles",
          optionC: "Nostrils",
          correctAnswer: "b) Spiracles",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Plants exchange gases during respiration through pores called ____. ",
          optionA: "Alveoli",
          optionB: "Spiracles",
          optionC: "Stomata",
          correctAnswer: "c) Stomata",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Respiration in dry seeds is crucial as they give rise to a baby plant during the process of ____. ",
          optionA: "Germination",
          optionB: "Fertilization",
          optionC: "Photosynthesis",
          correctAnswer: "a) Germination",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Respiration is the process of breaking down of ____ to release energy.",
          optionA: "Water",
          optionB: "Air",
          optionC: "Food",
          correctAnswer: "c) Food",
        },
        {
          question:
            "During cellular respiration, glucose is oxidized in the presence of ____ to release energy, water, and carbon dioxide.",
          optionA: "Nitrogen",
          optionB: "Oxygen",
          optionC: "Hydrogen",
          correctAnswer: "b) Oxygen",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Anaerobic respiration may produce alcohol or lactic acid in the absence of ____. ",
          optionA: "Carbon dioxide",
          optionB: "Water",
          optionC: "Oxygen",
          correctAnswer: "c) Oxygen",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The warm blood flowing through the blood vessels in the nostrils warms the inhaled ____. ",
          optionA: "Nitrogen",
          optionB: "Oxygen",
          optionC: "Carbon dioxide",
          correctAnswer: "b) Oxygen",
        },
        {
          question: "The common passage for air and food is the ____. ",
          optionA: "Trachea",
          optionB: "Pharynx",
          optionC: "Bronchi",
          correctAnswer: "b) Pharynx",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Exchange of oxygen and carbon dioxide takes place in tiny air sacs called ____. ",
          optionA: "Nostrils",
          optionB: "Bronchioles",
          optionC: "Alveoli",
          correctAnswer: "c) Alveoli",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The number of times a person inhales or exhales in a minute is called the ____ rate. ",
          optionA: "Heart",
          optionB: "Breathing",
          optionC: "Pulse",
          correctAnswer: "b) Breathing",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Insects like cockroaches have special air holes on their body surface called ____. ",
          optionA: "Alveoli",
          optionB: "Spiracles",
          optionC: "Nostrils",
          correctAnswer: "b) Spiracles",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Plants exchange gases during respiration through pores called ____. ",
          optionA: "Alveoli",
          optionB: "Spiracles",
          optionC: "Stomata",
          correctAnswer: "c) Stomata",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Respiration in dry seeds is crucial as they give rise to a baby plant during the process of ____. ",
          optionA: "Germination",
          optionB: "Fertilization",
          optionC: "Photosynthesis",
          correctAnswer: "a) Germination",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
